phamgalang@gmail.com
Portfolio: www.glenrage.com
Github: github.com/glenrage

# **GALANG** (Glen)

# **PHAM**

"I am passionate and prideful about my work no matter the job or task and believe expectations are meant to be exceeded."

### **SUMMARY**

Driven professional with broad technical and soft skill sets who thrives in agile, fast paced environments. 8 years of military experience has instilled leadership, communication, teamwork, and tenacity. Known for ability to meet deadlines and translate ideas into testable, maintainable, readable and reliable code.

### **WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS**

# **Fit-chievements** Full Stack Application, Solo Developer github.com/glenrage/fit-chievements

Full stack interactive social media SPA where users can upload and post fitness related achievements & follow other users & write comments. Built with React, Redux. Scalable, RESTful API built with Node, Express, MongoDB.

**Trance Trader** Client Application, Solo Developer github.com/glenrage/trance-trader

Stock Market Portfolio app that simulates stock trades with updated portfolio data displaying profits, losses and total portfolio value. Built with React.

**Equi-Gallery-VR** Full Stack Application, Team Developed github.com/glenrage/Equi-Gallery-VR

Full stack SPA that allows photographers to create a personalized gallery to upload 360\* photos & view them in Virtual Reality. Built with Angular, Node.

**Effort Manager** API Server Application, Team Developed github.com/CF-8-week-challenge/effort-manager

Lead developer in creating RESTful API for an iOS development team for a fitness app that tracks daily challenges with members organized in groups.

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## Oct 2016 - Present Full Stack Web Developer

Self Taught / Code Fellows, Seattle, WA

Learned Advanced Software Development in JavaScript. Implemented industry's best practices in writing quality, maintainable code and development processes. Integrated data through back end services and frameworks.

2006 - 2014 U.S Air Force (Supervisor, MX Data Analyst)

McChord AFB, WA, Worldwide multiple

Led and supervised aircraft maintenance teams on multiple deployments to hazardous combat zones. Performed maintenance data analysis in GO-81 to efficiently reduce unnecessary maintenance tasks by 20%.

#### **EDUCATION**

Feb - June 2017 Full Stack Web Development Intensive

Code Fellows, Seattle, WA

2009 - 2013 Bachelor of Science in Technical Management

Embry - Riddle Aeronautical University - Daytona Beach, FL

# PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

JavaScript ES6 / jQuery HTML5 / CSS / SASS

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### Core

Object Oriented &
Functional Programming
MVC / SPA
RESTful API / AJAX
Continuous Integration
Test Driven Development
Deployment(Heroku, AWS)
Debugging

#### Framework/Database

Angular React / React Native Redux Express

Node

Passport Authentication BootStrap MongoDB

PostgresSQL

### **Testing Frameworks**

Mocha / Chai Jasmine / Karma BrowserStack

### Systems/Tools

Git version control AWS Webpack / Babel

# SPOKEN LAN-GUAGES

English (Fluent)
Vietnamese (Fluent)